<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Course Structure | STA 418\518</title>
    <link>https://sta518.github.io/courses/course-structure/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://sta518.github.io/courses/course-structure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Course Structure</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://sta518.github.io/media/sta518-sticker.png</url>
      <title>Course Structure</title>
      <link>https://sta518.github.io/courses/course-structure/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modules</title>
      <link>https://sta518.github.io/courses/course-structure/modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sta518.github.io/courses/course-structure/modules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All materials for these modules will be shared through the Blackboard course site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module 1: What tools can we use for reproducible workflows?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topics: GitHub and Markdown; RStudio and RMarkdown; Git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module 2: How do we isolate and summarize information?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topics: Selecting columns; filtering out rows; summarizing variables; creating variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module 3: What is tidy data and how do we restructure data to be tidy?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topics: Tidy data; pivoting data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module 4: How do we efficiently combine datasets?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topics: Relational data; joins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module 5: How do we efficiently work with special variable types?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topics: Ordering characters; parsing strings; date-time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module 6: How do we effectively present data in graphics and tables?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topics: Grammar of graphics; tables as graphical objects; combining graphical objects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module 7: How do we create our own R functions?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topics: Functions for humans; conditional execution; function arguments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module 8: How do we apply functions to multiple items?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topics: Loops; functionals; multiple iteration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module 9: How do we fit statistical models to data?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topics: linear models; nested data; model output as tidy data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module 10: How do we use probability distributions to explore statistical concepts?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topics: Statistical simulations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module 11: How do we use resampling methods in statistical inference?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topics: Resampling; bootstrap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Module 12: How do we create interactive data products?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topics: Shiny apps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Targets</title>
      <link>https://sta518.github.io/courses/course-structure/learning-targets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sta518.github.io/courses/course-structure/learning-targets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are twenty Learning Targets for this course, which outline all of the important concepts in this course.
Ten Learning Targets are designated as &lt;strong&gt;Core&lt;/strong&gt; targets due to their nature in statistical computing and the other ten are designated as &lt;strong&gt;Supplemental&lt;/strong&gt;.
An important goal for you is to demonstrate competency, and eventually proficiency, in all of the Core Learning Targets and as many of the Supplemental Learning Targets as you can.
How you demonstrate proficiency in these Learning Targets is discussed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sta518.github.io/courses/course-grading/grading/#learning-target-checks&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Wrangling (DW): Import, manage, and clean data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DW.1&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;CORE&lt;/strong&gt;: I can import data from a variety of file types&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DW.2&lt;/strong&gt;: I can create or get data from the web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DW.3&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;CORE&lt;/strong&gt;: I can isolate information from a larger dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DW.4&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;CORE&lt;/strong&gt;: I can combine information from multiple sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DW.5&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;CORE&lt;/strong&gt;: I can identify if information is presented in a tidy format and restructure information to be in a tidy format&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DW.6&lt;/strong&gt;: I can put character data into a specified order&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DW.7&lt;/strong&gt;: I can use regular expressions and other string patterns to manipulate text data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DW.8&lt;/strong&gt;: I can use date/time data to extract portions or perform temporal calculations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Exploration (DE): Create graphical displays and numerical summaries of data for exploratory analysis and presentations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DS.1&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;CORE&lt;/strong&gt;: I can create tables of numerical summaries that draw attention to important comparisons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DS.2&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;CORE&lt;/strong&gt;: I can create graphical display of data that highlight key features&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DS.3&lt;/strong&gt;: I can combine multiple graphical displays or numerical summaries into an effective data product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Functional Programming (FP): Write R programs for randomization-based experiments and simulations from probability models&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FP.1&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;CORE&lt;/strong&gt;: I can write a function that accomplishes a common analysis task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FP.2&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;CORE&lt;/strong&gt;: I can use functional programming to apply a function to each element in data source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FP.3&lt;/strong&gt;: I can implement resampling methods to make conclusions about data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FP.4&lt;/strong&gt;: I can use common probability distributions to simulate data and explore statistical ideas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FP.5&lt;/strong&gt;: I can implement regression and tests of significance to analyze research questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FP.6&lt;/strong&gt;: I can generate personalized reports for multiple clients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Program Documentation (PD): Write clear, efficient, and well-documented R programs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PD.1&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;CORE&lt;/strong&gt;: I can use a project-based workflow to organize and run reproducible analyses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PD.2&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;strong&gt;CORE&lt;/strong&gt;: I can identify and correct common errors and in R programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PD.3&lt;/strong&gt;: I can explore new functions or packages and implement them into analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
